Finding Aid for the Philip Edward Chandler Papers LSC.0270
UCLA Library Special Collections
Philip Edward Chandler papers
circa 1930-1990
UCLA Library Special Collections
Chandler, Philip Edward
LSC.0270
3.0 Linear Feet (6 boxes, 3 oversize boxes, and 3 oversize folders)
Philip Edward Chandler (1908- ) worked in nurseries in Los Angeles area, and became a highly respected garden designer. He also taught at Santa Monica College for many years. The collection consists of correspondence, client files, plant lists, teaching and research notes, horticultural slides and photographs related to Chandler's career as a landscape architect.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Philip Edward Chandler, 1993.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 999641793606533
Biography
Chandler was born in 1908 in Columbia, Missouri; graduated, University of Missouri; after graduating, he moved to California and worked in nurseries in Los Angeles area; became a highly respected garden designer and taught at Santa Monica College for many years; developed annotated plant lists and catalogs for his classes; was a popular speaker and writer on horticulture and garden design.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, client files, plant lists, teaching and research notes, horticultural slides and photographs related to Chandler's career as a landscape architect. Also includes writings of Chandler and Bob Armacost, as well as personal files.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Landscape design client files.
Landscape design horticulture plant lists.
Writings by Chandler and others.
Landscape design horticulture teaching, research, and articles.
Southern California history notes by Bob Armacost.
Personal: Garden tours, symposia, travel, photographs, and slides.
Horticultural slides and photographs.
Landscape design -- California, Southern -- Archives.; Horticulturists -- California, Southern -- Archives.; Gardeners -- California, Southern -- Archives.; Chandler, Philip Edward--Archives.
- Landscape Design
  - Client Files
    - Ames, Charles, B., Mr. & Mrs.--Recommendations for Ames Ranch, Success Valley, Tulare County (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General note
      515 18th Street, Santa Monica.
    - Anderson, Richard, Mr. & Mrs. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      475 24th Street, Santa Monica.
    - Bain, Monica, 1984 / 1985. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      1230 Chickory Lane, Los Angeles.
    - Barker, Betty, 1989. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      1801 Westridge, Los Angeles.
    - Baser - Stoll, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      10633 Commerce Avenue, Tujunga.
    - Boson, Andy & Deborah--Includes planting plan and copies, February 7, 1977. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      144 Ocean Way, Santa Monica.
    - Brackey, Thomas, Mr. & Mrs., November 4, 1985. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      595 Radcliffe Avenue, Pacific Palisades.
    - Broderick, Roger, Mr. & Mrs., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      1211 Las Fulgas Road, Pacific Palisades.
    - Cabrillo Ave. Apartments - For Bernard and Larry Perloff, August 1989. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      1415 Cabrillo Avenue, Venice.
    - Carnes, William H., Mr. & Mrs., April 12, 1985. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      315 Bronwood, Los Angeles.
    - Coe, John Jr., Mr. & Mrs., December 17, 1987. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      511 N. Avenue, Los Angeles.
    - Colbert, Edward G., Dr. & Mrs.--Includes copy of planting plan by PC for Chandler and Lang, July 15, 1978. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      187 Homewood Road, Los Angeles.
    - Colby, Shirley, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      704 N. Palm Drive, Beverly Hills.
    - Colton, Albert, Mr. & Mrs., May 8, 1984. (Box 1, Folder 14)
      1061 Tellem Drive, Pacific Palisades.
    - Cooper, Harold, Mr. & Mrs., September 18, 1980. (Box 1, Folder 15)
      470 S. Bentley Avenue, Westwood.
    - Dickey, Robert, Mr. & Mrs., July 5, 1980. (Box 1, Folder 16)
      764 Ranch Lane, Pacific Palisades.
    - Diemer, William, Mr. & Mrs., September 23, 1978. (Box 1, Folder 17)
      16322 Akron, Pacific Palisades.
    - Dooley, James L., Mr. & Mrs., August 2, 1979. (Box 1, Folder 18)
      344 18th Street, Santa Monica.
    - Draper, Dexter, Mr. & Mrs., 1982. (Box 1, Folder 19)
      1247 Rimmer Avenue, Pacific Palisades.
    - Eadie, Verone, Mrs., April 6, 1977. (Box 1, Folder 20)
      250 Amalfi Drive, Santa Monica.
    - Faermark, Selma--With planting plan and copy (Box 1, Folder 21)
      5258 Babcock Avenue, North Hollywood.
    - Fine, Stuart & Marsha, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 22)
      11800 Allaseba Drive, Los Angeles.
    - Flaherty, Dundas (Dan) & Sandria--[file empty] (Box 1, Folder 23)
      3749 Malibu Vista Drive, Malibu.
    - Gertsley, Paul--Planting plan, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 24)
      101 Ocean Avenue, J-3, Santa Monica.
    - Gibbons-Fly, Sheila, Mrs.--With photos, November 27, 1987. (Box 1, Folder 25)
      6771 Wondermere Road, Malibu.
    - Gilbert, Arthur, Mr. & Mrs., May 1987. (Box 1, Folder 26)
      427 Wynola, Pacific Palisades.
    - Given, Bert, Mr. & Mrs., 1981. (Box 1, Folder 27)
      12316 16th Helena Drive, Brentwood.
    - Glenn--Planting plan. See also: Lucovici, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Gloege, Terry, Mr. & Mrs.--With site plan, 1983. (Box 1, Folder 29)
      152 Greenfield Avenue, Los Angeles.
    - Goodman, Bernard, Mr. & Mrs., 1984. (Box 1, Folder 30)
      7941 Flight Place, Los Angeles.
    - Gorb, Jna (?) & Laurel--With 2 copies of site / planting plan, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 31)
      806 Indiana Avenue, Venice.
    - Graham, William, Mrs., 1982. (Box 1, Folder 32)
      554 Moreno Avenue, Los Angeles.
    - Hay, Robert, Mr. & Mrs.--With copies of site plan and planting plan, photographs, July 1985. (Box 1, Folder 33)
      101 Sterling Lane, Wilamette, Illinois.
    - Hearst, G.R., Mrs., May 1977. (Box 1, Folder 34)
      318 N. Rockingham, Brentwood.
    - Henderson, Joyce, April 1984. (Box 1, Folder 35)
      1016 San Vicente, Santa Monica.
    - Howard, Elton, Mr. & Mrs., September 1980. (Box 1, Folder 36)
      447 26th Street, Santa Monica.
    - Hrafnuson, Robert & Sandra--With site plan (Box 1, Folder 37)
      Palmdale.
    - Hult, J.L., Mr. & Mrs., January 1982. (Box 1, Folder 38)
      1338 19th Street, Santa Monica.
    - Hill, Arthur, Mr. & Mrs., June 1989. (Box 1, Folder 39)
      1515 Club View Drive, Los Angeles.
    - Ingersoll, John, Mr. & Mrs., October 1986. (Box 1, Folder 40)
      21315 Lighthill Drive, Topanga.
    - Jackson, Parker, Mr. & Mrs., January 1984. (Box 1, Folder 41)
      792 San Lorenzo, Santa Monica.
    - Jacobson, Jerry, Mr. & Mrs., April 1975. (Box 1, Folder 42)
      2276 S. Beverly Glen, Los Angeles.
    - Johnson, Bradford & Carol, September 1980. (Box 1, Folder 43)
      537 Alta Avenue, Santa Monica.
    - Jokl, Robert H., Mrs., March 1983. (Box 1, Folder 44)
      563 N. Bundy Drive, Los Angeles.
    - Kaplan, Abner & Marie, April 1990. (Box 1, Folder 45)
      4012 Stalward Drive, Rancho Palos Verdes.
    - Katz, Martin & Wendy, May 1990. (Box 1, Folder 46)
      462 Mesa Road, Santa Monica Canyon.
    - Langridge, Colin, Mr. & Mrs., January 1988. (Box 1, Folder 47)
      14907 Camarosa, Huntington Palisades.
    - Le Gendre, Jody / Waiskopf, Kim, November 1981. (Box 1, Folder 48)
      4022 Madelia Avenue, Sherman Oaks.
    - Linden, Charles, Drive (Box 1, Folder 49)
      4055 Madelea Avenue, Sherman Oaks.
    - Langridge, Colin, January 1990. (Box 1, Folder 50)
      14907 Camarosa, Pacific Palisades.
    - Mann, Ruth, Mrs., February 1979. (Box 1, Folder 51)
      231 Notteargenta Road, Pacific Palisades.
    - Marx, Ernest, July 1985. (Box 1, Folder 52)
      Sunset Boulevard, Palisades Riviera.
    - McCall, John, Mr. & Mrs.--With site / planting plan, August 1977. (Box 1, Folder 53)
      259 Ocampo Drive, Huntington Palisades.
    - Milder, Alvin, Mr. & Mrs., June 1980. (Box 1, Folder 54)
      134 Greenfield, Los Angeles.
    - Moore, Stella, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 55)
      1035 Embury, Pacific Palisades.
    - Morrison, Donald, Dr. & Mrs., January 1989. (Box 1, Folder 56)
      258 Denslow Avenue, Los Angeles.
    - Murphy & Kress, Incorporated--With 2 sketches, November 1989. (Box 1, Folder 57)
      2401 Main Street, Santa Monica.
    - Murray, Ronald, Mr. & Mrs., April 1976. (Box 1, Folder 58)
      520 S. Westgate, Los Angeles.
    - Odin, John W., Mr. & Mrs.--With site sketch and planting plan, March 1981. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      659 Kingman Avenue, Santa Monica.
    - Otero, Joseph, Mr. & Mrs., June 1979. (Box 2, Folder 2)
      261 N. Bowling Green Way, Los Angeles.
    - Page, Michelle, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      1538 Yale Street, Santa Monica.
    - Palisades Presbyterian, June 1985. (Box 2, Folder 4)
      15821 Sunset Boulevard, Pacific Palisades.
    - Perloff, Bernard, Mr. & Mrs., June 1988. (Box 2, Folder 5)
      1133 Georgina Avenue, Santa Monica.
    - Perloff & Webster--Architectural site plan, design by Steven Erhlich, August 1989. (Box 2, Folder 6)
      321 Hampton Court, Venice.
    - Peterson, A., Mrs., November 1978. (Box 2, Folder 7)
      13125 Sunset Boulevard, Los Angeles.
    - Preonas, George, Mr. & Mrs., March 1977. (Box 2, Folder 8)
      714 Adelaide Drive, Santa Monica.
    - Quick, Michael, Mr. & Mrs.--With site plan, 1989. (Box 2, Folder 9)
      543 7th Street, Santa Monica.
    - Roberts, Eugene, Mrs., August 1982. (Box 2, Folder 10)
      2106 El Roble Lane, Beverly Hills.
    - Rubinstein, Ben, Mr. & Mrs., 1989. (Box 2, Folder 11)
      456 25th Street, Santa Monica.
    - Ruby, George, Mr. & Mrs., December 1981. (Box 2, Folder 12)
      12312 12th Helena Drive, Los Angeles.
    - Rush, John & Mary Anne, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 13)
      26827 West Live Oak Court, Agoura.
    - Russell, Drew, Mr. & Mrs.--With site / planting plan and copy, December 1978. (Box 2, Folder 14)
      417 N. Bowling Green Way, Los Angeles.
    - Schotz--With photographs of fountain types, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Schotz, Jon / Wheeler, Patti, 1984. (Box 2, Folder 16)
      701 21st Place, Santa Monica.
    - Schotz, Michael, Dr. & Mrs., 1982. (Box 2, Folder 17)
      332 Medio Drive, Los Angeles.
    - Schroeder, Allen, Mr. & Mrs.--Site plan / planting plan, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 18)
      17872 Tramonto, Pacific Palisades.
    - Shaw, Robert, Mr. & Mrs., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 19)
      2767 Forrester Drive, Los Angeles.
    - Silverman, Barry, Mr. & Mrs.--With site plan, August 1985. (Box 2, Folder 20)
      408 Sycamore Road, Santa Monica.
    - Sitkoff, Sandra, Mrs. (Box 2, Folder 21)
      10325 Northvale, Los Angeles.
    - Sjoberg, Helen, Mrs., 1983. (Box 2, Folder 22)
      330 23rd Street, Santa Monica.
    - Smith, George Andrew., Mr. & Mrs., 1982. (Box 2, Folder 23)
      630 Frontera, Pacific Palisades.
    - Sorrento Grill / Drew, Beatrice, Mrs., 1979. (Box 2, Folder 24)
      723 Pacific Coast Highway, Santa Monica.
    - Span, Robert & Crystal, 1989. (Box 2, Folder 25)
      16800 Charmel, Pacific Palisades.
    - Sprong, Eloise, Mrs., 1982. (Box 2, Folder 26)
      1945 Westridge, Los Angeles.
    - Staenberg, Zach, 1989. (Box 2, Folder 27)
      1815 Point View, Los Angeles.
    - Stanton, Ernest, Dr. & Mrs., November 1978. (Box 2, Folder 28)
      1525 Georgina Avenue, Santa Monica.
    - Stevens, Tim, Mr. & Mrs.--First page of planting plan only, 1978. (Box 2, Folder 29)
      15461 Albright, Pacific Palisades.
    - Stewart, Maxine, Mrs., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 30)
      545 Lucaro, Pacific Palisades.
    - Strauss, Glen, Mr. & Mrs., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
      445 25th Street, Los Angeles.
    - Valley, George, Mr. & Mrs., 1979. (Box 2, Folder 32)
      2827 Wigtown Road, Los Angeles.
    - Viersen, Richard, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 33)
      28603 Rothrock Drive, Rancho Palos Verdes.
    - Webster, Martin, 1981. (Box 2, Folder 34)
      140 S. Gunston Drive, Los Angeles.
    - Wells, W.E., Miss, 1989. (Box 2, Folder 35)
      2789 McConnell Drive, Los Angeles.
    - Wold, Mary, Mrs., 1983. (Box 2, Folder 36)
      746 Norway Lane, Los Angeles.
    - Yarrow, G.I., Mr. & Mrs.--With planting plan and copy, August 1983. (Box 2, Folder 37)
      928 20th Street, Santa Monica.
    - Adams, Sydney, Mr. & Mrs.--Site plan, planting plan and copy, 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
      466 Homewood Place, Los Angeles.
    - Baser - Stoll--Planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Beard, Ronald S., Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan by Chandler & Lang, 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 5)
      14915 Corona Del Mar, Pacific Palisades.
    - Broderick, Roger, Mr. & Mrs.--Front garden, rear garden planting plans, n.d.; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Carpenter, Gerald, Mr. & Mrs.--Copy of planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 7)
      10852 Marietta, Culver City.
    - Coe, John Jr., Mr. & Mrs.--Rear garden planting plan by Chandler and Lang, 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 8)
      511 N. Bristol, Brentwood.
    - Cooper, Harold, Mr. & Mrs.--Site plan by Jane Waisman, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Dickson, Richard, Mr. & Mrs.--Copy of planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 10)
      620 S. Sierra Bonita, Pasadena.
    - Dooley, James L., Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Draper, Dexter, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan, March 1982.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Flaherty, Dundas, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan, 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 13)
      3749 Malibu Vista Drive, Sunset Mesa, Malibu.
    - Goodman, Bernard, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan and copy, 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 14)
      7941 Fight Place, Westchester.
    - Hay, Robert, Mr. & Mrs.--Preliminary planting plan, planting plan, October 29, 1984.; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Hellinger, Bernard, Dr. & Mrs.--2 copies of planting plan by Chandler and Lang, 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 16)
      S. Bedford Drive, Beverly Hills.
    - Herr, Sam, Mr. & Mrs.--Copy of planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 17)
      19452 Twin Hills Place, Northridge.
    - Hill, Arthur, Mr. & Mrs.--Site plan, planting plan, n.d.; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Hrafnuson, Robert & Sandra--Planting plan and copy, 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Johnson, Bradford & Carol--Copy of front garden design, 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 20)
      537 Alta, Santa Monica.
    - Katz, Martin & Wendy--Site plan, planting plan, 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Langridge, Colin, Mr. & Mrs.--Site plan, planting plan and copy, 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 22)
      14907 Caramrosa, Pacific Palisades.
    - Lindenbaum, Colin, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan and copy, 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 23)
      611 10th Street, Santa Monica.
    - Loewenstein, Richard, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan and copy, 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 24)
      2138 Grenfield, West Los Angeles.
    - Ludovici, Lucia and Glenn, Gregory--Planting plan, 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 25)
      12561 Indianapolis, Los Angeles.
    - Montana Association--Planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 26)
      429 Montana, Santa Monica.
    - Moyer, Geoffrey, Dr. & Mrs.--Site plan / planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 27)
      720 Lachman Lane, Pacific Palisades.
    - Newmark, Gretchen--Planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 28)
      429 Montana Avenue, #C, Santa Monica.
    - Public Park--Pacific Palisades--Site plan / planting plan - 2 copies - by Chandler and Lang, 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 29)
      Antioch & Sunset.
    - Park, Helen, Mrs.--Copies of 2 separate planting plans by Chandler and Lang, 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 30)
      306 E. Mission, Santa Barbara.
    - Passman, Donald, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan, 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 31)
      2728 Monte Mar Terrace, Los Angeles.
    - Quick, Michael, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan and 2 copies, 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Rauch, Thomas, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan and copy, 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 33)
      510 N. Bristol, Brentwood Park.
    - Rice, Kevin, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan and copy. By Philip Chandler for Chandler and Lang, April 1980.; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 34)
      2158 Veteran, Los Angeles.
    - Rubinstein, Joseph, Mr. & Mrs.--Site plan, planting plan and copy, 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 35)
      456 5th Street, Santa Monica.
    - Silverman, Barry, Mr. & Mrs.--Site plan, planting plan, n.d.; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 36)
      408 Sycamore Road, Santa Monica Canyon.
    - Sjoberg, Helen, Mrs.--Planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Sork, Lawrence, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan by Chandler and Lang, 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 38)
      228 S. Carmelina, Los Angeles.
    - Smith, George Andrew, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan and copy, 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 39)
      630 Frontera, Huntington Palisades.
    - Span, Robert, Mr. & Mrs.--Site plan, planting plan, n.d.; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 40)
      1688 Charmal Lane, Pacific Palisades.
    - Sprong, Eloise, Mrs.--Site plan, planting plan, n.d.; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Stern, Robert, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 42)
      711 Georgina, Santa Monica.
    - Stevens, Tim, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Strauss, Glen--Site plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 44)
      Santa Monica.
    - Thomas, John, Mr. & Mrs.--Front garden, rear garden planting plans., n.d.; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 45)
      957 7th Street, Santa Monica.
    - Valley, George, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Gibbons - Fly, Sheila, Mrs.--Planting plan, 1987.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Farren--Planting plan copy for A. Lee Shelbourne & Associates (?), n.d.; 1 item. (Box 10)
      1000 Enchanted Way, Pacific Palisades.
    - Cooper, Harold--Copy of planting plan by Chandler & Lang, Jane Waisman, 1 item. (Box 10)
      470 S. Bentley, Los Angeles.
    - Fogarty, Joseph, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 10)
      10740 Wellworth Avenue, Los Angeles.
    - Coe, John Jr., Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 10)
      511 N. Bristol, Los Angeles.
    - Alice Keck Park Memorial Garden--Plant list. Grant Castleberg, landscape architect, 1978 May 31.; 2 items. (Box 10)
    - Bauer, Edwin, Mr. & Mrs.--Copy of planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 10)
      2741 McConnell Drive, Los Angeles.
    - Brentwood Tract Map, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 10)
    - Brief, Christopher, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan and copy, 2 items. (Box 10)
      502 N. Alta Drive, Beverly Hills.
    - Bruckner, David, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 10)
      3742 Mountain View, Los Angeles.
    - Cabrillo Ave. Apartments--Copy of irrigation system by Bob Galbreath, ground floor plan, February 28, 1989.; 1 item. (Box 10)
      Ted Tanaka, architect, Fran Hotchkiss, landscape architect.
    - New Manse--Planting plan, February 1985.; 1 item. (Box 11)
      900 El Medio.
    - Perloff, Bernard, Mr. & Mrs.--Site plan, copy of planting plan, n.d.; 2 items. (Box 11)
      1133 Georgina, Santa Monica.
    - Perry, Douglas H., Mrs.--Planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 11)
      12 Latimer Road, Rustic Canyon.
    - Punj--Copy of roofing plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 11)
      3812 Tesoro Road, Rancho Palos Verdes.
    - Quick, Michael, Mr. & Mrs.--Copy of planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 11)
    - Karp, Robert, Mr.--Planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 11)
      3561 Colonial Avenue, Los Angeles.
    - Molasky, Andrew, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan, 1 item. (Box 11)
      10369 Tennessee Avenue, Los Angeles.
    - Killeen, Jo. P., Mr. & Mrs.--Copy of planting plan by Chandler & Lang, March 1980.; 1 item. (Box 11)
      362 South McCadden Place, Los Angeles.
    - Greenblatt, E.L., Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan and copy, 2 items. (Box 11)
      5945 Wright Crest Drive, Culver City.
    - Howard, Elton, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 11)
    - Gilbert, Arthur, Mr. & Mrs.--Sketch, original planting plan and 2 copies, 4 items. (Box 11)
      427 Wynola Street, Pacific Palisades.
    - Manley--Original and copy of planting plan, 2 items. (Box 11)
    - Staenberg, Zach--Planting plan and copy of planting plan, 2 items. (Box 12)
      1815 Point View Street, Los Angeles.
    - Williams, Albert P., Mr. & Mrs.--Copies of planting plan, n.d.; 2 items. (Box 12)
      508 12th Street, Santa Monica.
    - Strauss, Glen, Mr. & Mrs.--Copy of planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 12)
      445 25th Street, Santa Monica.
    - Schotz, John, Dr.--Planting plan, January-March 1982.; 1 item. (Box 12)
    - Schotz, John, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 12)
    - Travis, William, Mr. & Mrs.--Planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 12)
      622 20th Street, Santa Monica.
    - Wells, W.E., Miss--Planting plan, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 12)
- Landscape Design / Horticulture
  - General
    - Photos [slides] by Joe Seals, p. 61(#12-18), May 1982. 1872. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Illustrations
    - Photographs. (Box 7)
  - Illustrations [Photo]
    - California sycamore--plantanus racemosa--Black and white photo, 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Illustrations [Slides]
    - Plant specimens--pp.17(#18)-18(#8), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Plant specimens, landscapes--pp.18(#15)-22(#1) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Cactus, etc.--pp.29(#14)-31(#17), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Small plants for small places (lecture with notes)--pp.52(#16)-53(#6)--See also Box 4, folder 13, Small plants for small places, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Fences--p. 48(#10)-48(#15), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Uncommon ornamentals--pp.53(#7)-54(#17), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Uncommon materials--pp.50(#7)-52(#15), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - English gardens--pp.54(#18)-56(#7), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Landscape--pp.47(#12)-58(#6) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified--pp.58(#7)-61(#5) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous--pp.61(#6-11), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Designing gardens in California (lecture and notes)--pp.1-4 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Garden details--Snapshots mounted on scrapbook pages. Brentwood, Santa Barbara, Claremont, Mirandy residence, 1968.; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Outlines for Talks, Lectures, Articles Published
    - Low growing shrubs with architectural value--Folders 1-23 designated by PC as ... of possible future use, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Landscape of Man's Private World (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Nature of Landscape Design (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Basic Garden Skills, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Landscaping the Small Garden (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Shade Gardens, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Ornamental Horticulture and Garden Design (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Use of Natives in Planting Design, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Easy Ferns for Southern California Gardens (Other Than Tree Ferns), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Annuals in California, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - What is a Garden, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Color in the Tropical Garden, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Christmas Decor in for Southern California, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Plants in the Christmas Tradition--Seasonal Decor in the Southern California Home, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Plant Materials and Planting Design (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Cultivation in Pots, Tubs, or Boxes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Most Useful Trees for Pacific Palisades, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Return to California, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Fuchsias, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Hugh Evans, Horticulturalist by Esther Perl, March 1975. (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - A Riot of Orange, Yellow, Salmon, Violet and Lavender (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Notes on public gardens, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Plant Lists by Philip Chandler
    - Basic shrubs for Southern California gardens. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Basic trees for landscape use in Southern California. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Basic vines, wall shrubs and espaliers--Southern California. (Box 3, Folder 3)